do it properly
[music]
that it has happened
Hello friends Namaskar I am Sunil Rohilla,
your financial planner. I plan for
your children's future, their higher
education, their marriage, daughter's
diagnosis policy,
tension free pension for your retirement.
Also I cover Cooperative Suresh in Factory Insurance,
Fresh Shopping Research, in this
I ignore employer scheme, workman compensation
policy, all this.
Friends, today I have come to you with a very important
topic. In the previous series,
we had told you in the previous video
that what things should be kept in mind before taking a health insurance policy.
I had given you those five tips. This
time I want to tell you how many benefits are there in a health insurance policy
and which benefits
you need.
Before designing any policy,
friends, I am starting with that. First of all,
whenever we plan for any insurance
policy,
before taking a health insurance policy, we have to
see which is the company that
we are selecting, is it a white
company, does it have any  We are going to get facilities
that keeping our age criteria
in mind, are they being successful,
whatever repairs we have done in
medical, are we getting coverage in today's date,
so for example, if you are a lead
couple, a newly married couple, and someone
is planning an insurance policy,
friends, they do not want a general policy and they
want a special policy which
can give them many benefits in the future, such as an
app which has maternity cover, suppose if a
baby is born to them, then the
cost of its delivery should be
covered by their health insurance policy, friends, this
policy also has this feature, in this policy
many companies cover it in 2 years and some
companies cover it in 3 years and along with this,
if we talk clearly about a
single company, such as
Star Health in our India, which is our IVF
treatment, if anyone has any problem related to children, there is
no good news for them yet, there is
IVF treatment for that treatment and the
father of this treatment is the
patient, friends, it costs 1 to 2 lakh rupees
and this is why everyone is interested in this
treatment  Who gets the water and they
spend a lot of days like this without a child, friends
because the treatment is very expensive,
if we talk about Star Health Insurance,
they have given a very good facility that
they have covered the BJP in Star Health Insurance,
secondly I will tell you another feature of Star Help,
friends, like all of us, all
our companies have
different USPs from different companies,
so in any kind of policy, if
you take this sum insured of 5 lakhs, then
your restoration of 5 lakhs above 5 lakhs is
free, it
means your policy gives treatment of part plus 5 lakhs,
friends, if we talk about
Star Health, in this policy
you are also getting highway cover and if you do it for 5 lakhs and
you are
getting free restoration benefit in that, in other
such policies we will
see that you get 5 lakhs on 5 lakhs and secondly
we have to pay attention that if we take a
policy of 5 lakhs in any insurance policy,
how much bonus will it get in the next year, if
we do not make any claim here this year, then how much will it get
in the next year  You will
get a claim, means what will be the value of that policy, so if we
talk about no claim bonus, then
Tata Magic has brought a very good feature in no claim bonus.
In Tata Magic,
in a policy of Rs 15 lakh, next year you will get
50%, 50% pyramid for 2 consecutive years. If
your policy runs for 3 years, then you will get 210%, that is, instead of
five lakhs, the policy becomes of Rs 10 lakh.
This is the state where you
can take any treatment and its 75 lakhs
free cap. In this way, we can say that this
year take a policy of Rs 5 lakh. Next year, if
you apply for this no claim bonus, if you have
not taken any treatment at your place and
apply no claim bonus, then in that
your policy becomes of Rs 7.5 lakhs instead of Rs 5.25 lakhs and you
can take treatment at Rs 7.5 lakhs
and for you also, Viman Kishan overlap has been made for a
single tender disease, then
Tata Magic also covers your bill of Rs 2 lakh.
One more USP of this stage, I would like to tell
that if we want to
go to any country for treatment for our disease, then
Tata  AIG covers
that Tata is providing a global cover global
treatment card so this is a very good recipe
of Tata Magic now let's talk about some
insurance policies having no claim bonus of
2%, in some 50%, in some 20%,
everyone will do their own thing. Now talking about this one
company, what is
its service for the common man, for every person and no
company provides health sum insured for less than 3 lakhs
but
I have seen only one such company
and this is this company in which you will get a policy of 1 lakh as well as
1.5 lakhs
and if someone's condition is very bad
then sometimes they will cover 50 lakhs, sometimes
you can also take a small policy for you, what I
mean to say is that whenever you are planning any service, keep
these points in mind
that which policy you are blending,
which company is
finalizing, which
age group's benefit are you looking at from which company,
every insurance company has different
benefits, different carriers.  You have to
see
what treatments you need in the coming 5 years, depending on your age,
related to the hospital. Next, let's
talk about this. If we are
youngsters, delivery and IVF is very important for this cycle.
If someone is 45 to 50 years old,
they should take such a policy in which
your OPD is covered early
because around 40, some disease has already entered inside and it
suddenly goes away, but when the treatment
of the operation is done in two or four years, then
after four years,
friends, it is very important that we have to keep this
point in mind. When
taking a policy for a senior citizen
or any other person, if you
need this policy quickly, then I will
say very important that you
can also take some special plans,
like for a different plan. If we
talk about someone who is a diabetic, then
Star Health gives a policy to cover diabetes for treatment,
if someone does not have internet then he
gets internet. The rest is
planned after studying their report. If someone has
cancer, any
If someone gets a medical illness or a major illness and he
wants that in future, many people in my family have had
cancer in the previous generation or our
grandfather or our father has been
diagnosed with cancer, then why should we
not take such a rider, why should we add a CIR rider in the policy
which has a Critical
Illness Rider, friends,
and if we talk about riders, then
this is for this festival, if you have any medical
illness, it is a disease worth 25 lakhs, the demand is
only 25 lakhs, who took your switchboard and
that illness occurs tomorrow, then
you can take a sigh of relief and take benefit in it, the second
thing I am going to tell you is very important for you, right now that is, if
you take any health
insurance policy, then along with that
you need
disability cover, back cover, accidental
cover policy cover, cancer policy cover, all these,
now you can add it in it, there are some
insurance policies, Star Health
also has it, Tata AIG also has it in which
you get this cover inbuilt, so every
company has 4236 products
They are designed differently for different areas. It is very important that the common
man is covered keeping in mind all his needs.
It is very
important that we have to see that this
company has the
right benefits as per our age and our requirements
and our treatment is covered in it. Along with this, I would
like to talk about one thing that today if we get any disease or
problem, we get admitted at a place 204 km away from home.
After getting admitted, if
our wife or any member of our family
wants to visit us, then one
percent or two percent of the sum insured is the
amount and it was said that
in some companies there is a limit of
20 to 240. The benefit
of the travel is called the limit. It
means that one traveler per patient can go to visit any of our
sick policy holders.
Another very
important feature which the health
policy provides is the ambulance cover.  Normal
ambulance is now available, we can use it two, three, four times a
year, there is a
dead drop charge and along with this,
if we assume that there is a critical illness,
because when an accident happens and
someone in Mumbai has to be admitted to the hospital immediately, then this
special
administration company, Wipro company,
school
helicopter service or any other company will
prepare a special flight in case of emergency and
this flight will pick him up from here
and drop him to the hospital there,
for rescue, when we need it,
this facility of air ambulance is also
very important, we should also pay
attention to this and those who work in the field, who
work in the market,
friends, it is very important, they must have
a PI cover in their policy,
this is not there in the European and their policies,
so they should keep this point in mind in their policy
whether there is an
inbuilt policy of Rs 5 lakh and a risk cover of Rs 5 lakh,
this is also installed along with the five lucky
policy, that interest rate company
gives us disability by bringing five lakhs and
that Tata Magic  If you are a star, you will get both.
So friends, all companies have different
features. Different products are made for different purposes.
You have to see
which one suits you best. Along with this, we will talk about it.
If
someone has any problem in work, it was
heard that the accurate test of eggs costs a
thousand rupees,
you get that too for free. Now let's talk about
F12. If someone has kidney
failure and needs a kidney transplant, then
this is called organ donor
and window 10 facility. It is not necessary in every policy
that this is the policy period and if it is giving, then there is a
criteria in it. One company is
saying that we will
give treatment of Rs 50,000 to your organ donor and will leave 10 percent of the
time. There is a company which has a policy of Rs 5 lakh.
We give Rs 5 lakh to the donor as well and we
give him as much as he wants to meet the expenses. So,
this is also an important factor
which needs to be taken into consideration.
Along with this, there are many other things in it.  From the benefits and
every end diagnostics, it is wide like if
we have a CT scan and somewhere wires,
those expenses are also covered and let's talk about it that
some companies
also give us free health checkup every year along with two claim bonuses.
Hello friends, these are some important points
that in any policy of Prince,
we have to keep the company in mind, we have to keep the product in mind,
we have to keep the features in
mind and these features will be
in our mind and we will suffer in our own
way, so I think that we will be able to have
a policy plan with more benefits.
If this problem arises, friend,
I approach this policy, there is
no recovery in it, I have to
pay the bill by cheque, this is not covered, so I have to
say that the operation is only after 4 years and
what will be the benefit of this policy, if my kidney
stones are not getting removed, then these
many issues were coming, keeping those points in
mind, I have made this health insurance policy for you people, now to
educate the common man, thank you
sir, to make myself aware, to
make these different, I made this health
insurance policy.  I have
brought them in front of you in this video through features,
friends, it feels very good when I
try to teach and tell something to people somewhere or the other, that is because
if I have some knowledge, now the more I can spread it
among my friends, everyone will have
knowledge, everyone will be educated
and everyone will be able to get their details independently
and if you have got
an educational and informative message in this video of mine, then
I would like to request you to
like, share,
subscribe and press the bell icon, if you
press it then you will
get notifications of my upcoming videos regularly and thank you very much, take
care of your health, keep
drinking Kada etc., keep doing Yoga
and pay special attention to your food and diet, you will remain
fit, then I
think it will be very good and thank you once again,
Namaskar, please do that